然后让反质子的自旋反向
And reverse the spin on the antiproton...
γ变成了α
and γ becomes α...
乘以矩阵(-i,0)
Multiplied by a matrix of (-i,0)...
有成果了
And there we have it.
证明我九点过后就是一条废柴的证据
Conclusive proof that I am absolutely worthless after 9 o'clock.
谢尔顿...
Sheldon...
好了  好了
All right, all right.
我看穿了你们的诡计
I see what's going on.
万圣节前的装神弄鬼罢了
A little pre-Halloween hijinkery.
阴森的呜咽
A ghostly moan,
铁链的响声
a rattling of chains,
女巫的奸笑
a witch's cackle.
老套的鬼屋三元素
The trifecta of haunted house cliche.
普通人尖叫  哥只想睡觉
Instead of "eek," I say, "yawn."
谢尔顿...
Sheldon...
滴血之墙
Oh, the walls are dripping blood,
看上去假得就像把碳酸钠溶液
which looks nothing like a phenolphthalein indicator
碳酸钠溶液呈碱性  遇酚酞变红
滴进了酚酞里一样
exposed to a sodium carbonate solution.
"我们地狱里见谢尔顿"
"See you in hell Sheldon."
这话最恐怖的地方  是你忘了加逗号了
The most frightening thing about that is the missing comma.
好  很好
Okay, all right.
这招高
That one was clever.
缆绳上挂着个含磷的骨架
Skeleton with phosphorous on a zip line.
现身吧  快活的恶作剧者们[也是乐队名]
Come on out, merry pranksters.
该谢幕了
Take a bow.
你真该看看你刚才的表情
You should've seen your face.
有什么呀  不过就是稍稍受到惊吓
Yes, there's nothing quite like the slightly widened eyes
然后瞳孔小小地放大了一点
of mildly startled.
你就承认吧  谢尔顿
Come on, admit it.
我们吓着你了
We got you, Sheldon.
拜托  惊吓惊吓  有惊才有吓
Please, fright depends on an element of surprise.
而事实是
The simple fact is,
在能未卜先知的我面前
because I am much smarter than you,
你们两个臭皮匠的烂招  只是笑话
and able to anticipate your actions,
想吓到我诸葛亮
it is highly unlikely that you two rubes
门都没有
could ever surprise me.
他说的对吧
He's probably right.
我们吓不倒他  他太聪明了
We can't beat him. He's just too smart.
先生们
Gentlemen.
谁刚才赌他会晕倒来着
Who had money on "faints"?
我赌的是尿裤子
I had "pee his pants."
等等
Hang on.
看来我们都赌中了
Looks like everyone's a winner.
■
本字幕由 YYeTs人人影视 翻译制作
更多美剧原创翻译 请登陆 www.YYeTs.net
■
翻译：米小勒  海因里希  Tina  小蛮腰
后期：孤帆    时间轴：小e
■
校对：笑点王-赛太公  哭点后-猫太婆      总监：YY
生活大爆炸  第五季第七集
当心了  谢尔顿
Oh. Watch out, Sheldon.
这个《鬼马小精灵》可是个鬼-鬼-鬼-鬼啊
This little boy Casper is a g-g-g-ghost!
可笑
Droll.
那也可笑不过一个成年人
Not as droll as a grown man
晕倒在自己的一滩尿上
passed out in a puddle of his own urine.
的确太可笑了
That was pretty droll.
尿液中含氨
笑声中还带着一丝氨气的芬芳
With a hint of ammonia.
接着沾沾自喜着吓人的胜果吧  先生们
Yes, enjoy your japes, gentlemen.
觉得自己吓倒了一名胆小的大学学者
You think you've poked fun at a milquetoast academic.
可你们忘了一件事
Well, you've forgotten one thing:
我可是孤星州[德州别称]之子
I am also a son of the Lone Star state.
我可是彻头彻尾的德州人
I'm Texas through and through.
我们可会修理人了
And we know how to settle scores down there.
不信就去问  常被我们修理的墨西哥人
If you doubt me, ask Mexico.
辣妹出没  九点钟方向
Hot girl, nine o'clock.
别同时抬头看人家
Don't everybody look at once!
她来漫画书店做什么
What is she doing in a comic book store?
我不清楚  估计是迷路了
I don't know, she might be lost.
无所谓了  都学着点儿
Doesn't matter. Watch and learn.
-你好啊  -你好
- Hi.  - Hi.
呃...呃...呃
... it-it-it...
都闭嘴
Shut up.
你要买这期《Next Men》吗
Are you getting this Next Men?
是的  这是第二十一期的那本
Uh, yeah. It's issue number 21.
地狱男爵第一次登场的那期
First appearance of Hellboy.
我知道  我找了它很多年
I know. I've been looking for it for years.
-抱歉了  -要是我假装来泡你
- Sorry.  - Hey, if I pretended to hit on you,
我的美貌够不够让你分心  好让我把书偷走
could I distract you enough to sneak it away?
够的  但滥用超能美貌做坏事是不对的
Yes, but you'd be using your superpowers for evil.
该死  我在氪星的老爸禁止我用能力使坏
Damn, I'm forbidden by my Kryptonian father to do so.
Kryptonian  超人家族所在星系
我叫爱丽丝
I'm Alice.
我叫莱纳德
Leonard.
你真可爱  莱纳德
You're very cute, Leonard.
谢谢  你也是
Thanks. You, too.
这书你拿去吧
You know, go ahead and take it.
不  不行  这样我就做坏事了
No, no. No, no, I-I did evil.
你接受以物易物吗
Would you be open to a trade?
可以  没问题
Yeah, yeah, sure, I guess.
好吧  给
Okay. Here.
这是我的电话号码
This is my number.
记得打给我
Call me.
抱歉  手掌有点出汗
Sorry, palm's a little sweaty.
那是个什么词儿呀
What's that word?
-爱丽丝  -对哦  你的名字
- Alice.  - Oh, right, your name.
刚看成"爱鸡鸡"还纳闷呢
That makes more sense than "Penis".
回见了
Later.
我们亲眼目睹到你在漫画店成功把到妹吗
Did we just see you pick up a girl in a comic book store?
如果是真的  我要把你的肖像
'Cause if you did, you get your picture up there
挂在英雄榜上
on the Wall of Heroes.
没有吧  应该没有把到她
No, I don't think I picked her up.
更何况我还有家室呢
Besides, I have a girlfriend.
无所谓  你算是最成功的一个了
Doesn't matter. This is the closest anyone's ever come.
你入榜了  伙计
You're going on the wall, my friend.
一定要开信箱
Be sure to check the mail.
你还要提醒我几次呀
How many times are you gonna tell me?
-你没事吧  -没事
- What's with you? - Nothing.
我锲而不舍有什么奇怪的
It's not suspicious that I'm fixating.
我个性向来坚持不懈
It's consistent with my personality.
好吧
Right.
伙计们
Hey, guys.
又买万圣节糖果了啊
More Halloween candy?
你昨天不是刚买了一堆吗
Didn't you just buy a bunch of it yesterday?
那堆啊  吃完了
Oh. Yeah. That's gone.
万圣节和大姨妈一起来
It's a rough month when Halloween and PMS
我是屋漏偏逢连夜雨呀
hit at the same time.
莱纳德没时间聊天
Leonard doesn't have time to chat,
他要去开信箱
he has to get the mail.
你就不能消停会吗  我马上就开
Will you relax? I'll get it in a minute.
-你工作怎么样了  -快开信箱
- How was work?  - Open the mail!
等我一下
Excuse me.
几份广告而已  没什么重要的东西
A couple of circulars, nothing important.
-他怎么了  -等着瞧
- What's with him? - Hang on.
你是德州人又怎样  哥还是新泽西人呢
You might be from Texas, but I'm from New Jersey.
看这个
Check it out.
Jim Lee  美国韩裔漫画家
两年前的动漫展上吉姆・李帮我画的
Jim Lee drew this of me two years ago at Comic Con.
你穿的是什么呀
What are you wearing?
动漫展嘛  你懂的
Well, you know, it's Comic Con.
我是《霹雳猫》里的狮猫
I'm Lion-O from ThunderCats.
哇  肯定有不少女生对你"投怀送抱"吧
Wow, you must have gotten so laid.
没有  但洁西卡・阿尔芭有揉我毛毛的肚子
No. But Jessica Alba did rub my furry belly.
要看看我画的漫画吗
Want to see a comic I draw?
开玩笑吧  你自己有画漫画啊
You're kidding. You have your own book?
是的  灵感是来自我的生活
Yeah. It's kinda based on my life.
厉害啊
Cool.
看啊  你和一个上身打扮成
Oh, look. That's you having sex with a guy
楚巴卡 星战人物  浑身毛茸茸  像猩猩
楚巴卡模样的人在嘿咻
in the top half of a Chewbacca costume.
在动漫展上吗
Comic Con?
你以为是  不过非也
You'd think, but no.
你真有才  画得真好
You're very talented. This is really good.
你是不是...
Did you do...
我能用我的漫画换你的《地狱男爵》吗
So, can I trade you my comic for the Hellboy?
换我车子都行
You can have my car.
神啊
Oh, dear.
我的老天爷啊
Oh, dear...
妈啊  妈啊  妈啊
Oh, dear, oh, dear, oh, dear...
救命啊  救命啊  救命啊
Oh, dear, oh, dear, oh, dear.
洗手液  洗手液  洗手液  洗手液
Purell, Purell, Purell, Purell.
早上好  谢尔顿
Good morning, Sheldon.
今早是好啊
It is, isn't it?
哎呀  讨厌
Oh, bother.
每次都这样
Isn't that just always the way?
要用订书机  才发现没钉书针了
You go to staple something, and you're out of staples.
史泰博:  美国著名办公用品品牌  与订书针同字
老天  要是我早些在史泰博的时候
Gosh, I wish I'd known that earlier today
知道就好了
when I was at Staples.
那里有回形针啊
You ever think of paper clips right there?
不  我需要能把纸钉牢的东西
No, no, I need something more permanent to join these papers.
你不是把订书钉放在第一格抽屉的吗
Say, don't you keep staples in your top desk drawer?
不知道  也许吧
I don't know. Maybe.
行行好  看一下嘛
Be a lamb and check.
好吧
All right.
是哪个小可爱躲在这呀
Who do we have here?
是条蛇  一条吓人的蛇
It's a snake. A terrifying snake.
是不是哪个坏蛋把你丢到抽屉里啦
Oh, did some bad man put us in a drawer?
别装可爱说话了
Stop talking like that.
你应该被吓得说不出话来才对
You've been rendered speechless by fear.
咱们去生物实验室
Let's go to the biology lab
给你搞点美味的小白鼠来吃吧
and find you some nice yummy mice.
我居然想用蛇来吓唬印度佬
I tried to scare an Indian with a snake.
加油啊  库珀  你就这么点能耐吗
Come on, Cooper. You're better than this.
门没锁
It's open.
你现在有空吗
Hey, you got a minute?
当然  进来吧
Yeah, sure, come on in.
谢了
Thanks.
来点芝士通心粉吗
Want some mac and cheese?
不了  有乳糖  吃了会放屁
No. Lactose. Gas.
-酒呢  -不了  有亚硝酸盐  喝了会头痛
- Glass of wine?  - No. Sulfites. Migraines.
好吧  我本来想给你吃万圣节糖果
Okay, well, I'd offer you Halloween candy,
不过都吃完了
but that's gone.
怎么了
So, what's up?
好吧  我们以前不是约过会吗
Okay, we used to go out, right?
老天  总算想起来你是谁了
Oh, my God, that's where I know you from.
我碰到了点难题
I'm dealing with a situation
是跟感情有关的
and it's kind of about my love life,
我知道咱俩谈这个  可能有点尴尬
so I know that might be weird for us to talk about,
但在这方面  你也知道
but in this area, as you know,
我其他的朋友实在是  蠢得可以
all my other friends are just so stupid.
好吧  怎么回事
All right, what's going on?
这么不介意我跟你谈吗
So, you're okay talking about this?
-当然  -你不会觉得尴尬吧
- Yes. - You're sure it's not weird.
真的不会
It's okay.
好吧  如果有天你想和我谈
You know what, if you ever want to talk to me
你跟男人的感情问题
about a problem in your life with a guy,
我也愿意听
then I would be fine with that.
那好  现在就有个我以前好过的小子
Okay, good, because there's this one guy I used to date
他要是再这样拐弯抹角
who's about to be force-fed wine and cheese
我就要灌他吃红酒和芝士
if he doesn't get to the point.
好吧
Okay,
是这样的
here it is.
这样算不算偷腥  如果一个男的有女朋友
Is it cheating if a guy has a girlfriend...
应该算的
Yeah, probably.
别这样嘛
Come on.
对不起  你说
I'm sorry, go ahead.
我新认识一个女孩子  她人很好
I met this girl, and she's great.
跟我有很多共同话题
we have a lot in common.
那你们搞了吗
Did you guys do it?
没有  只是亲热了一下下
No. We just made out a little.
哎呦  瞧你个小坏蛋
Oh, look at you, you bad boy.
你跟她提过普丽娅吗
Did you tell her about Priya?
我也想提  可她的舌头在我嘴里呢
Well, I was gonna, but there were too many tongues in my mouth.
真恶心
That's gross.
现在的情况是
Here's the thing,
我不是那种四处偷腥
I-I'm not one of those guys who sneaks around
拈花惹草的男人
and sleeps with more than one woman.
好孩子
Well, good for you.
可问题是  我想成为那种男人
The problem is, I want to be one of those guys.
那就瞒着普丽娅  把那女的睡了
So sleep with the new girl and lie to Priya.
我不是那种人
Oh, that's not who I am.
那好  那就跟那女的一刀两断
All right, then break it off with the new girl.
也别草率行事
Now, let's not do anything rash.
她真的很正点
She's really hot.
既然你这么喜欢这个女孩子
If you like this girl so much,
那干嘛不跟普利娅分手
why don't you just end things with Priya?
普丽娅和我深爱对方
Priya and I are in love.
我们以后说不定会结婚呢
I think we could get married someday.
莱纳德  你是想找个两全其美的办法
Leonard, you're looking for a way to sleep with both women
好让你左拥右抱
and have everybody be happy about it.
终于说到点上了
Now we're getting somewhere.
你的第一直觉是什么
What does your gut tell you?
"去问佩妮  她知道该怎么做"
"Go ask Penny; she'll know what to do."
你好  霍华德
Hello, Howard.
我知道你们吓我是闹着玩的
I've realized that you scaring me was all in jest.
请容许我说  吓得很成功
Allow me to say, job well done.
完美
Perfect.
你在干嘛呢
What are you doing?
搞科研呢  你不会懂的
Science. You wouldn't understand.
那好  再见  我出门了
Hey, well, see you. I'm going out.
我以为你是要出门呢
I thought you were leaving the apartment.
我也以为  可我下不了决心
Yeah, me, too. I can't make up my mind.
你是不是担心外面的世界
Are you concerned because the world is filled
充满着疯狗和坏蛋
with big dogs and bullies?
不是  我正面临道德上的难题
No. I'm having a moral crisis.
如果需要帮忙的话
Well, if it's of any help,
我读过各种伦理学家的著作
I've read all the great moral philosophers,
美国著名作家及漫画家  以儿童书出名
包括苏斯博士的书哦
including Dr. Seuss.
死马当活马医吧
Oh, what the hell.
我本来要去见
I'm supposed to go see that girl
在漫画书店认识的那个女孩子  爱丽丝
from the comic book store, Alice,
可我不知道该不该去
but I don't know if I should,
因为我现在跟普利娅在一起
because I'm going out with Priya,
可她人又远在印度
but she's in India.
好吧  这么说现在的主题是性忠贞
All right. So the topic at hand is sexual fidelity.
苏斯博士在这方面估计靠不住
Probably won't be relying on Seuss here.
苏斯博士1960年著作
不过《一条鱼  两条鱼  红色的鱼  蓝色的鱼》
Although One Fish, Two Fish, Red Fish, Blue Fish
倒可能惊人的适用
might be surprisingly applicable.
继续
Go on.
那个
Well...
别人都说  人到了暮年
they say at the end of your life,
比起自己做过的事
you regret the stuff you didn't do
会更后悔没有做过一些事
more than the stuff that you did,
而我非常确定我很想跟爱丽丝"做"
and I'm pretty sure Alice is the stuff I want to do.
德国哲学家弗里德里希・尼采
You know, the German philosopher, Friedrich Nietzsche,
相信道德只是低等人群体
believed that morality is just a fiction
用来阻碍少数高等人的
used by the herd of inferior human beings
虚构事物
to hold back the few superior men.
死马还真给医活了
That actually does help.
值得一提的是  他后来死于梅毒
It's worth noting that he died of syphilis.
-管他呢  我去也  -你回家的路上
- Screw it, I'm going.   - On your way home,
-能不能买点橙汁回来  -拜托
- will you pick up some orange juice? - Do you mind?
我正在质疑我人生中很多的人事物呢
I'm questioning a lot of things in my life right now.
你喜欢橙汁也需要质疑吗
Is one of those things your fondness for orange juice?
-不用  -那就对了  纯果乐  要没果肉的
- No.  - Great. Tropicana, no pulp.
嗨  谢尔顿
Hey, Sheldon.
谁啊
Who is it!
沃罗威茨太太  是我  谢尔顿
It's me, Sheldon, Mrs. Wolowitz.
那不是我妈  是伯纳黛特
That's not my mom, it's Bernadette.
真的吗  真分不出来
Really? That's very unsettling.
嗨  谢尔顿
Hi, Sheldon.
-嗨  -有事吗
- Hi.  - What's up?
我刚想到  我一直都还没正式恭祝过
It just occurred to me that I never formally congratulated you
你们即将到来的婚事
on your pending nuptials.
于是我跳上首班车
So I hopped on
一路狂奔过来跟你握手道贺
the first bus and hightailed it down here to shake your hand.
快把手伸过来  你这家伙
Put 'er there, you old so-and-so.
再过12小时  咱俩就一起上班了
Well, I-I'm gonna see you at work in...12 hours
你怎么不等上班了再跟我握手呢
don't you think it could have waited until then?
我的老天  我怎么就没想到呢
Holy smoke, why didn't I think of that?
你果然比我聪明  霍华德・沃罗威茨
You're a better man than I, Howard Wolowitz.
快把手伸出来  你个小聪明
You put 'er there, you son of a gun!
那随你吧
Whatever.
天啊
My...oh...
我
it's...
天啊  霍华德
Oh, my God, Howard!
你对他做了什么
What did you do?
只是个无恶意的万圣节恶作剧而已  看
It was a harmless Halloween prank. Look.
霍华德有心脏病  你又不是不知道
Howard has a heart condition! You know that!
我还以为他那是瞎编的呢
Well, I thought he made that up.
犹太人不是常有
I-Isn't hypochondria
疑病症的问题吗
a common idiosyncrasy of Jewish people?
这是肾上腺素
This is adrenaline --
我们得把这个注射到他的心脏里
we're gonna have to inject it into his heart.
-我们得做吗  -是你做
- We are?  - You are.
我可没那么大劲扎穿他的胸腔
I'm not strong enough to get it through his chest plate,
而且机会只有一次
and we've only got one shot.
不  我做不来
Oh, no! I can't!
快点
Hurry!
咱们时间不多了
We're running out of time!
-好吧  -快扎呀
- Okay.  - Just do it!
上帝啊
Oh, God!
一  二
One...two...
三
three!
不给糖就捣蛋  笨蛋
Trick or treat, bubbeleh.
什么
What?
不是吧  你们居然设局耍我
No. You mean this was all a ruse?
我怎么会笨成这...
Oh, how could I be so stu...
该死的  不行
Damn it, I can't.
我不能这样
I can't do this.
是因为我的舌环吗
Uh, is it my tongue stud?
要是有穿舌环就会吓到你
'Cause if that freaks you out,
那待会儿你会更大吃一惊哦
you're in for a real surprise later on.
不  不是
No, no, no.
是我不能跟你这样
I-I can't do this.
相信我  我真的很想
Believe me, I really want to.
-但是呢  -但是我有女朋友了
- But...?  - But I kind of have a girlfriend.
你开什么玩笑
Are you kidding?
你不介意咱俩只做朋友吧
You're cool with you and me just being friends, right?
我真不敢相信
I don't believe this.
等等  我...你不相信哪部分
Wait, I don't... Which part?
我真是笨到家了
I'm so stupid.
我还以为我终于遇上了个好人呢
I thought for once I'd met a good guy,
结果你也只不过又是一个混蛋而已
but you're just another jackass.
不  不  你误会了
Oh, no, no, you have it wrong.
不  我本来是要当个混蛋
No. I-I was going to be a jackass,
但是我克制住了
but I stopped myself.
我决定做个好人  所以
I stayed a good guy, so...
我还是不跟你滚床单了
I'm gonna pass on the sex.
但是你要知道  这并不代表你不够辣
But you should know, that's not a comment on your hotness
这只是说明我品德高尚
but on my goodness.
这也算是我的超能力了吧
That's kind of my superpower.
我就像是  好人队长
I'm, like, Captain Good Guy.
没啥了不起的
It's okay.
做了对的选择
Did the right thing.
我悔得肠子都青了
You idiot!
普丽娅
Hey, Priya.
亲爱的  一切都好吗
Hey, sweetheart. How's it going?
不怎么样
Uh, not so good.
咱俩得谈谈
We have to talk.
好像很严重的样子啊  怎么了
Oh, sounds serious. What's up?
好吧  事情是这样的
Okay, uh...here it is.
我认识了一个女生  我们接吻了
I met this girl and I kissed her,
我觉得很内疚
and I feel terrible about it.
但都结束了  绝无下次
But it's done, it's never gonna happen again.
我真的非常非常抱歉
And I am so, so sorry.
莱纳德  别紧张
Leonard, relax.
没事的
It's okay.
真的吗
It is?
是啊  这种事情很正常
Yeah, these things happen.
人之常情嘛
They happen to everybody.
天啊  你真是太好了
Oh, my God, you are amazing.
我怎么这么命好呀
I mean, I don't deserve you.
等  等会  你说"人之常情"是什么意思
Wh-what do you mean "everybody"?
莱纳德  我不知道该不该说
Leonard, I didn't know if I should tell you,
不过我好像也背叛你了
but I kind of cheated on you, too.
什么叫好像
Kind of?
几周前
A couple of weeks ago,
我跟我前男友上床了
I slept with my ex-boyfriend.
所以说  我们俩都犯了点小错误
So, I guess we both messed up a little.
不  我是犯了点小错  你可是犯了大错
No, no, I messed up a little. You messed up a lot.
咱这又不是在比赛
Well, it's not a competition.
就是比赛  而且你赢了
Oh...yeah, it is, and you won.
对  对不起  我要下线了
I-I-I'm sorry, I have to go.
老天爷你玩我啊
I don't believe this.
吓到了吧  小混蛋  现在我们扯平了
Bazinga, punk. Now we're even.